Inventory of the American National Red Cross records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Paris Headquarters, 1918-1922
  - Commission for Europe, 1918-1922
    - The History of the American National Red Cross, 1950
      - The American National Red Cross in World War I, 1917-1918, volume IV, by G.R. Gaeddert, Historical Department, Washington, D.C., 1950
        Box/Folder 200: 19
      - The American National Red Cross in World War I, 1917-1918, volume IV, by G.R. Gaeddert, Historical Department, Washington, D.C., 1950 (Reel 301)
        Box/Folder 200: 20-23
      - Liquidation Activities of the American National Red Cross in the Post-Armistice Period, World War I, volume XXVIII, by Joseph Bykofsky, Historical Division, Washington, D.C., 1950
        Box/Folder 200: 24
      - Foreign Relief in the Post-Armistice Period, World War I, volume XXIX, by Joseph Bykofsky, Historical Division, Washington, D.C., 1950
        Box/Folder 200: 25
- Miscellany, 1917-1928
  - Russia-Eastern Base, Constantinople Unit, 1919-1921
    - Supplies, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 201: 1-3
    - General routine for all warehouses, 1920 (Reel 302)
      Box/Folder 201: 4
    - The Solar Plexus of the War, Armenian Bureau of Publications, London, 1918
      Box/Folder 201: 5
    - Dorozhnaya karta Vsevelikogo Voiska Donskogo, 1919
      Box/Folder 201: 6
    - Reports, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 201: 7
    - A. Staritzky, 1920
      Box/Folder 201: 8
    - Social survey, 1920
      Box/Folder 201: 9
    - Correspondence, 1919-1921
      Box/Folder 201: 10-12
    - Prisoners and refugees, 1921
      Box/Folder 201: 13
  - American Relief Administration, Russian Unit, 1919-1928
    - Appeals, 1919-1922
      Box/Folder 201: 14-17
    - Banks that did not handle food drafts, letters, 1921-1922
      Box/Folder 201: 18
    - Correspondence transmitting Moscow-New York debit and credit memoranda, 1921-1923 (Reel 303)
      Box/Folder 201: 19-20
    - Medical Division, reports, Ekaterinoslav District, 1922-1923
      Box/Folder 201: 21
    - Medical Division, reports, Ekaterinoslav District, 1922-1923
      Box/Folder 202: 1
    - Closing Remittance Division--Disposition of all closing sent to Russia, 1923
      Box/Folder 202: 2
    - Correspondence, daily reports, Prague to London, 1921-1922
      Box/Folder 202: 3-11
    - Correspondence, daily reports, Prague to London, 1921-1922 (Reel 304)
      Box/Folder 202: 12-13
    - Medical Division, list of supplies, 1922
      Box/Folder 202: 14
    - Transportation, South Russia, Sevastopol, reports, 1920
      Box/Folder 202: 15
    - Letters of appreciation, 1921-1923
      Box/Folder 202: 16-17
    - Economic Situation in Europe, by Herbert Hoover, Secretary of Commerce, Washington, 1921
      Box/Folder 202: 18. Includes clippings, 1927-1928
    - Food Remittance Department, 1921-1922
      Box/Folder 202: 19
    - Lists of banks, distributing centers, and post offices, 1921
      Box/Folder 202: 20
    - Finance and Accounting Division, receipts, 1922
      Box/Folder 202: 21-22
    - Finance and Accounting Division, receipts, 1922
      Box/Folder 203: 1-3
    - American Siberian Repatriation Committee, 1919-1922 (Reel 305)
      Box/Folder 203: 4
    - United States Food Administration, Mission to Poland, 1919
      Box/Folder 203: 5
    - Commission for Germany, correspondence, reports, 1917-1921
      Box/Folder 203: 6-10
    - British Red Cross, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 203: 11-12
    - Austrian Red Cross, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 203: 13
    - Danish Red Cross, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 203: 14
    - Commission for Palestine, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 203: 15
    - Memorandum re relations of Red Cross, YMCA, and other similar societies to the Sanitary Service, U.S. Army, 27 August 1918
      Box/Folder 203: 16
    - Commission for Western Russia and Baltic States, 1918-1922
      Box/Folder 203: 17
    - American Committee for American Prisoners, 1917-1918
      Box/Folder 203: 18
    - Camps for prisoners of war, Germany, inspection reports, 1916
      Box/Folder 203: 19
    - Commission for the Balkan States, 1918-1920
      Box/Folder 203: 20
    - Warehouses, Switzerland, 1917-1919 (Reel 306)
      Box/Folder 203: 21-22
    - Commission for Great Britain, 1918
      Box/Folder 203: 23
    - Commission for Europe, 1918-1921
      Box/Folder 203: 24
    - China Famine Relief, 1921
      Box/Folder 203: 25
    - Commission for Russia, Siberia, 1918
      Box/Folder 203: 26
    - Commission for Russia, Siberia, 1918
      Box/Folder 204: 1-2
    - Czechoslovak Red Cross, 1919
      Box/Folder 204: 3
    - Baron Schliffenbach, A., 1919
      Box/Folder 204: 4
    - Hôpital pour Enfants, Evian, France, appreciation letters, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 204: 5-6
    - La Municipalité de Paris, Official
      Box/Folder 204: 7
    - Receptions for ARC commissioners, 1918
    - Care Committee for Soldiers and Sailors, 1918
      Box/Folder 204: 8
    - Transportation Department, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 204: 9
    - Personnel, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 204: 10
    - Sales, shipments, receipts, 1917-1919
      Box/Folder 204: 11-12
    - Sales, shipments, receipts, 1917-1919 (Reel 307)
      Box/Folder 204: 13
    - American Nurses Club, 1917-1918
      Box/Folder 204: 14
    - ARC in Italy, Board of Inquiry and Discipline, minutes of hearings, 1918
      Box/Folder 204: 15-17
    - Commission for Great Britain, report of Military Relief Department, ARC, 1 December 1918
      Box/Folder 204: 18
    - Printed forms from departments and bureaus, 1919
      Box/Folder 204: 19
    - Fourteenth Division Bulletin, published by the Territorial, Insular and Foreign Division, ARC, Washington, D.C., 1918
      Box/Folder 204: 20
    - "ARC Commission, Plan of Organization and Rules and Regulations", Paris, 11-Oct-17
      Box/Folder 204: 21
    - "The Home Sector", a weekly for the new civilian conducted by the former editor of the Stars and Stripes, New York, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 204: 22
    - Aux Orphelins de la Guerre, Oeuvre d'Assistance, Paris, 1918-1920.
      Box/Folder 204: 23-24. Includes clippings
    - Lists of American prisoners, Frankfurt, 1918
      Box/Folder 205: 1-3
    - Lists of American prisoners, Frankfurt, 1918 (Reel 308)
      Box/Folder 205: 4-5
    - War Council, minutes of meetings, 1917-1919
      Box/Folder 205: 6-11
    - Lists of ARC overseas personnel (only residents of the United States and Canada), 22 April 1920
      Box/Folder 205: 12-14
    - Lists of ARC overseas personnel (only residents of the United States and Canada), 22 April 1920 (Reel 309)
      Box/Folder 205: 15-17
  - ARC commissions, reports on activities, 1917-1922
    - Italy, 1917-1922
      Box/Folder 206: 1-8
    - Italy, 1917-1922 (Reel 310)
      Box/Folder 206: 9-16
    - Eastern Base, Constantinople Unit, 1921
      Box/Folder 206: 17-18
    - Balkan States, 1919
      Box/Folder 206: 19
    - South Russian Unit, Crimea, 1920
      Box/Folder 206: 20
    - Poland, 1919
      Box/Folder 206: 21
    - Near East, 1920
      Box/Folder 206: 22
    - Western Russia and Baltic States, 1919-1920 (Reel 311)
      Box/Folder 207: 1-4
    - Russian prisoners in Germany, 1919
      Box/Folder 207: 5
    - Joint Distribution Committee of the American Fund for Jewish War Sufferers, answers to questionnaire, undated
      Box/Folder 207: 6
  - ARC Headquarters, Paris, Conferences, 1919
    Box/Folder 207: 7
    - Stanford Library Bulletin, Stanford University, vol. 5, no. 26, March 19, 1953
      Box/Folder 207: 8
    - Confidential file, 1919-1922
      Box/Folder 207: 9-10
    - Romania, newspapers, 1920
      Box/Folder 207: 11
- Printed Matter, 1906-1963
  - Bulletins, ARC, 1906-1921
    - Potomac Division Bulletin, ARC, Washington, 1918-1921
      Box/Folder 207: 12-14
    - The Junior Red Cross, supplement, 1921 (Reel 312)
      Box/Folder 207: 15
    - Central Division Bulletin, Chicago, Illinois, 1920
      Box/Folder 208: 1
    - Red Cross Service, by Central Division, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 208: 2
    - The Lake Division News, Cleveland, 1917-1921 (Reel 313)
      Box/Folder 208: 3-10
    - The Lake Division News, Cleveland, 1917-1921 (Reel 314)
      Box/Folder 208: 11
    - Northwestern Division Bulletin, Seattle, Washington, 1917-1921
      Box/Folder 208: 12-16
    - Northern Division Bulletin, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1919-1921 (Reel 315)
      Box/Folder 209: 1-4
    - Red Cross Briefs, Southern Division, Atlanta, GA, 1919-1921
      Box/Folder 209: 5-8
    - Gulf Division Bulletin, New Orleans, LA, 1918-1920
      Box/Folder 209: 9
    - Gulf Division Bulletin, New Orleans, LA, 1918-1920 (Reel 316)
      Box/Folder 209: 10-11
    - Important Items, ARC, Southwestern Division, St. Louis, MO, 1917-1921
      Box/Folder 209: 12-17
    - Important Items, ARC, Southwestern Division, St. Louis, MO, 1917-1921 (Reel 317)
      Box/Folder 209: 18
    - Pacific Division Activities, Arizona-California-Nevada, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 209: 19-20
    - Pacific Division Activities, Arizona-California-Nevada, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 210: 1-2
    - The News Letter, Atlantic Division, New York, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 210: 3-6
    - ARC Rays, Mountain Division, Denver, CO, 1918-1921
      Box/Folder 210: 7-8
    - ARC Rays, Mountain Division, Denver, CO, 1918-1921 (Reel 318)
      Box/Folder 210: 9-12
    - Red Cross clippings, Philadelphia, PA, 1917-1921
      Box/Folder 210: 13-18
    - New England Division Bulletin, 1919-1921 (Reel 319)
      Box/Folder 210: 19-21
    - ARC Bulletin, London, 1918
      Box/Folder 211: 1-2
    - Insular and Foreign Division ARC, Washington, D.C., 1918-1921
      Box/Folder 211: 3-6
    - The American Red Cross Bulletin, The National Headquarters, Washington, D.C., 1906-1913 (Reel 320)
      Box/Folder 211: 7-8
    - The American Red Cross Bulletin, The National Headquarters, Washington, D.C., 1906-1913 (Reel 321)
      Box/Folder 211: 9-10
    - The Speakers' Bulletin, issued by Speakers' Bureau at National Headquarters, Washington, D.C., 1920
      Box/Folder 212: 1
    - The American Red Cross Bulletin, The National Headquarters, Washington, D.C., 1917-1920
      Box/Folder 212: 2
    - The American Red Cross Bulletin, The National Headquarters, Washington, D.C., 1917-1920 (Reel 322)
      Box/Folder 212: 3-4
    - The American Red Cross Bulletin, The National Headquarters, Washington, D.C. (Reel 323)
      Box/Folder 212: 5
    - The Red Cross Bulletin, Volume II, The American Red Cross Commission to Western Russia and the Baltic States, Riga, Latvia, 1921
      Box/Folder 212: 6
    - Bulletin, the League of Red Cross Societies, Geneva, Switzerland, Vol. II, 1921
      Box/Folder 213: 1
    - Nouvelles de l'Agence Internationale Des Prisonniers de Guerre, by Comité International de la Croix-Rouge, Genève, 1917-1918.
      Box/Folder 213: 2-3. See also oversized box 222
  - Magazines, 1913-1920
    - Red Cross Magazine, the official organ of the ARC, 1913-1917 (Reel 324)
      Box/Folder 213: 4-5
    - Red Cross Magazine, the official organ of the ARC, 1913-1917 (Reel 325)
      Box/Folder 213: 5
    - Red Cross Magazine, the official organ of the ARC, 1917-1920 (Reel 326)
      Box/Folder 214: 1-2
    - Red Cross Magazine, the official organ of the ARC, 1917-1920 (Reel 327)
      Box/Folder 214: 3-5
    - Red Cross Magazine, the official organ of the ARC, 1917-1920 (Reel 328)
      Box/Folder 214: 6-8
    - Red Cross Magazine, the official organ of the ARC, 1917-1920 (Reel 329)
      Box/Folder 214: 9
    - Red Cross Magazine, the official organ of the ARC, 1920
      Box/Folder 215: 1-2
  - Reports, 1914-1963
    - Annual, 1914-1923
      Box/Folder 215: 3-5
    - Annual, 1914-1923 (Reel 330)
      Box/Folder 215: 6-7
    - Financial, 1917-1918 (Reel 331)
      Box/Folder 215: 8-9
    - Red Cross Service Record, Accomplishments of Seven Years 1939-1946, Office of Program Research, ARC, Washington, D.C.
      Box/Folder 215: 10
    - Report of the Department of Military Affairs, January to July, 1918, Rome
      Box/Folder 215: 11
    - Annual Report of the Secretary, 1918-1919, New York County Chapter, New York
      Box/Folder 215: 12
    - Report of the New Orleans Chapter, New Orleans, June 30, 1919
      Box/Folder 215: 13
    - Report of War Relief Activities, 1917-1919, District of Columbia Chapter
      Box/Folder 216: 1
    - Report of ARC Operation, 1912-1920, Prepared for the Tenth International Conference of the Red Cross at Geneva, 30 March 1921
      Box/Folder 216: 2
    - Six Months' Report of the Secretary General ARC in France, Paris, 1918
      Box/Folder 216: 3
    - Report of the Director, Department of Civil Affairs, ARC in France, April 1, 1918, Paris
      Box/Folder 216: 4
    - Europe's Need, by Henry P. Davison, Chairman of the ARC War Council during the war, 7 April 1920 (Reel 332)
      Box/Folder 216: 5
    - Report Upon Transfusion of Blood, For the Recently Injured in the U.S. Army, by Medical Division of the ARC in France, 1918
      Box/Folder 216: 6
    - Three Years of Work for Handicapped Men, report of the Activities of the Institute for Crippled and Disabled Men, by John Fairies, Ph.D., New York, 1920
      Box/Folder 216: 7
    - ARC in Italy, Department of Medical Affairs, Rome, 1918
      Box/Folder 216: 8
    - The Red Cross Centenary, 1863-1963, Report on International Commemorations Presented by the League of the ARC Societies, undated
      Box/Folder 216: 9
    - An International Adventure, What the ARC Is Doing for the Civilians of France, July 1917 - May 1918, Paris, France
      Box/Folder 216: 10
    - War Medicine, vol. II, no. 1, Paris, August 1918, published by the ARC Society in France for the medical officers of the American Expeditionary Forces
      Box/Folder 216: 11
    - Trench Fever: Report of Commission Medical Research Committee American Red Cross, Oxford University Press, 1918 (Reel 333)
      Box/Folder 217: 1
    - Missing List and Requests for Details of Death and Burial, nos. 10 and 11, 1919, ARC Headquarters, Paris
      Box/Folder 217: 2
    - New York-New England Hurricane and Floods: Official Report of Relief Operations, Washington, D.C., 1938 (Reel 334)
      Box/Folder 217: 3
  - Pamphlets, instructions, manuals by ARC departments, 1916-1964
    - Charters and by-laws, December, 1917
      Box/Folder 217: 4
    - Bureau of Development, 1917-1918
      Box/Folder 217: 5
    - Department of Military Relief, 1916-1918
      Box/Folder 217: 6
    - Department of Chapters, 1917
      Box/Folder 217: 7
    - Women's Bureau, 1917
      Box/Folder 217: 8
    - Nursing Service, 1916-1920
      Box/Folder 217: 9
    - Department of Civilian Relief, 1918
      Box/Folder 217: 10
    - Bureau of Finance and Accounts, 1918
      Box/Folder 217: 11
    - Territorial, Insular, and Foreign Department, 1918
      Box/Folder 217: 12
    - War Department, 1917
      Box/Folder 217: 13
    - Department of Civilian Relief, 1917-1918
      Box/Folder 218: 1
    - Medical Department, 1917-1918 (Reel 335)
      Box/Folder 218: 2-3
    - An Atlas of Gas Poisoning, Medical Research Committee, ARC, 1918
      Box/Folder 218: 4
    - Typhus Fever with Particular Reference to the Siberian Epidemic, by Richard P. Strong, 1920
      Box/Folder 218: 5
    - Shell Shock and Its Lessons, by Elliot G. Smith and T.H. Pear, London, 1917
      Box/Folder 218: 6
    - International Committee of the Red Cross, 1917-1963
      Box/Folder 218: 7-8. Includes International Red Cross Committee in Geneva, 1863-1943, Zürich
    - International Committee of the Red Cross, 1917-1963 (Reel 336)
      Box/Folder 218: 9
    - Introduction to the Red Cross, ARC, Washington, D.C., 1950
      Box/Folder 218: 10
    - The Role Call, a Masque of the Red Cross, by Percy Mackaye, Red Cross Christmas Roll Call, National Headquarters, ARC, Washington, D.C., 1918
    - The Greatest Freewill Offering in History, ARC, Washington, D.C., undated
      Box/Folder 218: 11
    - For Humanity's Sake, by Clyde E. Buckingham, Washington, D.C., 1964
      Box/Folder 219: 1
    - The Pittsburgh Chapter ARC, compiled and prepared for publication by the Chapter History Committee, 1922
      Box/Folder 219: 2
    - The Red Cross Chapter at Work, by Marie Cecile and Anselm Chomel, Indianapolis, 1920 (Reel 337)
      Box/Folder 219: 3
    - Prisoners of the Great War, Authoritative Statement of Conditions in the Prison Camps of Germany, by Carl P. Dennet, Boston and New York, 1919
      Box/Folder 219: 4
    - Woodrow Wilson, His Life and Work, by William Dunseith Eaton and Harry C. Read, 1919
      Box/Folder 219: 5
    - The War, the World, and Wilson, by George Creel, New York and London, 1920 (Reel 338)
      Box/Folder 219: 6
  - Card Index
    Box 220
- Oversized Materials, 1917-1920
  - Commission for Balkan States--Fourth Red Cross Roll Call, 1920, scrapbook and photographs
    Box/Folder 221: 1-7
  - Commission for Switzerland, financial chart and analysis of accounts, 1918-1919
    Box/Folder 222: 1
  - Commission for Great Britain, financial reports, statistical data, 1918-1919. (Reel 339)
    Box/Folder 222: 2. See also boxes 54-55
  - Printed matter, 1918-1919
    - The Red Cross Bulletin of the ARC in Italy, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 222: 3
    - Red Cross Bulletin, issued by the ARC, 4, Place de La Concorde, Paris, 1918
      Box/Folder 222: 4
    - Red Cross Bulletin, issued by the ARC, Corner of the Rue des Pyramides and the Rue de Rivoli, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 222: 5
    - Red Cross Bulletin, issued for the ARC in Europe, Paris, 1919
      Box/Folder 222: 6
  - Russian White Army posters, 1918-1919
    Box 223
  - Second Red Cross War Fund Campaign, banner, 1918
  - Commission for Belgium--Home des Internés, drawings, undated
  - Commission for Great Britain--American Nurses Club, minutes book, 1917-1919
    Box 224
  - Commission for Italy, scrapbook of clippings from Italian newspapers, 1918
- Videotapes, 1995
  - Your Red Cross Heritage, circa 1995 (Tape cabinet cabinet)
  - Elizabeth Perry, 1995 (Tape cabinet cabinet)